[SPEAKER_01]: Fletcher was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Fletcher was offered jobs several times, as a manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he stayed there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was getting that World Series ticket and making good money.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had good coaches.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had old catcher that managed the Red Sox in Detroit later.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a coach there for a long time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ralph Howe.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, McCarthy, like I said, all he had to do to drive the lineup down here was tell her anything about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who didn't know?
[SPEAKER_01]: And with Ruffing and Gomez and Murphy to lead.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that raises a question.
[SPEAKER_00]: How important is the managerial function?
[SPEAKER_00]: If you have good talent, even with McCarthy, you're going to win.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Casey Stengel.
[SPEAKER_00]: Look what Stengel did with the Boston Bees and the Brooklyn Dodgers, last place teams.
[SPEAKER_00]: He comes to the Yankees, and now he's in the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I thought Casey Stengel was one of the worst managers I ever heard about.
[SPEAKER_01]: When they named Yogi Burr manager of the Yankees, I just damn near kicked my tail when I read this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Two weeks later, the Red Sox named Johnny Pesky manager of the Red Sox, and I did kick my tail.
[SPEAKER_01]: Knowing both of them well, I liked Johnny Pesky.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played with him in Louisville.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then he went up to Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played with him all these years.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's still with the Red Sox, a friend of mine.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I didn't think he had managerial ability.
[SPEAKER_01]: And anybody, the team is what makes the manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: The manager doesn't make the team, in 90%.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, there's times, I said to you,
[SPEAKER_01]: Not second-guessing, but I see every ball game of Red Sox game.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I don't always agree with McNamara on his change of pitches or the strategy.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I'm wrong about half the time, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Maybe he's wrong half the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't second-guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like, a lot of people second-guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anybody can second-guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't do that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I say, right now, this is the wrong thing to do, the wrong move, what he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or, why didn't he do this?
[SPEAKER_01]: brought him over to study.
[SPEAKER_01]: No two managers played exactly alike.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's more or less of a hunch, but like they say, those teams that you're talking about, nobody could have won with those teams that he had earlier.
[SPEAKER_01]: And anybody could have won with the teams he had when he was with the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_01]: So is he a great man?
[SPEAKER_00]: So they call him a great manager now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, sure.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, look, McCarthy.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it's the tyranny of statistics, then, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, here's what I've always maintained.
[SPEAKER_01]: We used to play 154 games a year.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's 50 of those games that you're going to lose.
[SPEAKER_01]: In spite of all you do, that other team's time to win.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's 50 games.
[SPEAKER_01]: There may be 50 games that you're going to win.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're gone.
[SPEAKER_01]: But at least that's 100 games.
[SPEAKER_01]: Those 54 games in the middle here is where your manager comes in.
[SPEAKER_01]: You see, there's games you're going to win 13 to 2, and there's games you're going to lose 2 to 1.
[SPEAKER_01]: In spite of all you did, you played your best and you lost.
[SPEAKER_01]: But there's other games, those in-between games.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's where your manager comes in.
[SPEAKER_01]: The games that could go either way.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the way I look at it.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's my philosophy.
[SPEAKER_01]: The manager pitching, I think, is at least 75% of the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can prove that with statistics any way you want to look at it.
[SPEAKER_01]: 75% of managing is handling that pitching stuff.
[SPEAKER_01]: How you set up your rotation and pitching, when do you take that starting pitcher out and bring in your relief, or who do you got here?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's managing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now there's certain ball players going to behave a certain way, certain, because some ball players need a kick in their ass, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Certain ball players need a pat on the back.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is part of managing, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: To be a manager,
[SPEAKER_01]: You've got to be with the press and everybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've got to be a PR man.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've got to be a psychologist, psychoanalyst for the different temperaments and all along the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's complicated.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've got to meet the press, the public.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a complicated job.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a job I don't want.
[SPEAKER_01]: In 1949, when I asked, I asked Conan for my release.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, no, I'm not going to release you.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're going to keep you until you die.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, like, hell, you are.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know what I'm going to do.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, some of these people don't know and want to stay in the game.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I said, I'm going home.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know what I want.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've got my plans.
[SPEAKER_02]: You seem to be a very astute student of the game.
[SPEAKER_02]: I wonder why you didn't get in a pitching coach.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't care about being a coach, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess it's something like this.
[SPEAKER_01]: I consider myself a student of the game.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I learned a lot of baseball under Uncle Billy Dixon in Austin.
[SPEAKER_01]: In the four years I was up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I guarantee you, the certain things that I see every day in the major leagues that I learned in college.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uncle Billy Dixon was there for thirty some odd years, recognized as one of the best coaches there was in college baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was off a job in Pro Body with himself.
[SPEAKER_01]: When he left, about the time I finished, Bibb Falk took over.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bibb was an old, an ex-longhorn.
[SPEAKER_01]: He played back in the teens and early 20s.
[SPEAKER_01]: Had a lifetime batting average of over 300.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bibb Falk was a good outfielder, good hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bibb took over.
[SPEAKER_01]: In the major leagues today, there's players that can't come together, can't even sacrifice.
[SPEAKER_01]: They don't even know how to approach the plate and position themselves.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they go to spring training for six weeks.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I can understand, like Ted Williams or Jim Rice, that they were going to call it on the clock.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I've seen pictures that don't even know how to go.
[SPEAKER_01]: They don't know the fundamentals of it, the segregation.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you couldn't bunk for Billy Dish, you couldn't play on his ball court.
[SPEAKER_01]: And another thing is this run-down play.
[SPEAKER_01]: Getting the man in the hot tub.
[SPEAKER_01]: I asked Johnny Pesky last year down in Florida.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, Johnny, when the hell are you people going to learn to make that run-down play?
[SPEAKER_01]: And he acted like he didn't know what I was talking about.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, hell, last year, within two weeks' time, I said, you want a ball game because the other team could not make
[SPEAKER_01]: the run-down play, didn't make it properly.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, two weeks later, you lost the ball game because you couldn't make the run-down play.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he didn't even know what I was talking about.
[SPEAKER_01]: But we learned both things, the basics.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was never disappointed in my life when I signed in June, went to Moultrie, Georgia.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, the season was half over, and they'd established, and the rest
[SPEAKER_01]: my time until I got to Louisville in the American Association.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never learned a damn thing about the press corps.
[SPEAKER_01]: I already knew that.
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't teach it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But some of the managers that put in the moderators I don't think was working.
[SPEAKER_01]: Excuse me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I studied it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I studied it.
I studied it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I studied it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I studied it.
I studied it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I studied it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I studied it.
I studied it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I didn't know that there was quite as much difference in... Vermont, the showmaker, and the circus.
[SPEAKER_01]: They bring them back and make them watch Major League Ball for a week.
[SPEAKER_01]: because you lose the perspective, you can make it look better, you know, down here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can see kids up here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Last night, they're up here, they're moving, they're doing this, you know, you don't do that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But they're doing it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm talking about college World Series class folks.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the field is, they don't position themselves right on the ground.
[SPEAKER_01]: They don't throw the ball exactly right.
[SPEAKER_00]: How long a schedule did you play in college compared to what they play today?
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't play near as many games, not near as many games.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went to Texas because I wanted to play baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was a walk-on.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't have a scholarship.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I went there.
[SPEAKER_01]: because Texas University had the best reputation in the country back in the 30s.
[SPEAKER_01]: While I was there my senior year, I pitched against two major league ball clubs in Clarkfield and Austin.
[SPEAKER_01]: I pitched against St. Louis Browns and Philadelphia Athletics while I was in my senior year.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went into the league with the bases loaded,
[SPEAKER_01]: against St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_01]: Two balls and no strikes on the hitter, who was Roger's hornet, was at the plate.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's through, like Joe Cronin was through.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, he's through playing, hasn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was manager probably, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was managing the ballplay.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was at bat.
[SPEAKER_01]: The count was two balls and no strikes, and the base was loaded.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know I've got to get the ball over before he strikes.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's way back in the box, and I said, I'll wait for him to get ready to find out if he decided he was.
[SPEAKER_01]: When you knew he was, he stands so far away.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he just looked at that first pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: I came back accidentally, I guess, but I got the fastball over again, nearly at the same place.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hit the ball over the right center field fence in Clark Field, nine miles.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was my only pitch against him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I pitched the last three innings of the ball game against St. Petersburg Bay.
[SPEAKER_01]: Stroke out six of the next nine after I got third.
[SPEAKER_01]: But that's the reason I went to Texas.
[SPEAKER_01]: One year, we played six Texas league teams early in the season.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had been in camp a month, and they'd been in camp a week.
[SPEAKER_01]: We played Tulsa.
[SPEAKER_01]: We played Minneapolis, which is a triple-A ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: We beat Texas league teams five out of six games.
[SPEAKER_01]: But they were just in camp a week, using their weaker pitchers, rookies.
[SPEAKER_01]: We'd been in training for a month or more.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we had some good ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of the players that I was with at Texas University, when I was there, there were 18 boys.
[SPEAKER_01]: My teammates, some of them were seniors when I was a freshman and some were freshmen when I was seniors, covered seven or eight years.
[SPEAKER_01]: But there was 18 boys of Texas Longhorn baseball team that played double-A ball or better.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's part of that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But that's the reason I wanted to go to school.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could have gone to school here in southwest Texas, closer, lived out here in the country on the ranch when I grew up.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I won't go to Texas like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, what do you think about their schedule?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is it overemphasized, maybe?
[SPEAKER_02]: They play something like 70 ball games.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: They play six games in three days.
[SPEAKER_01]: The doubleheader for two days.
[SPEAKER_00]: Are those doubleheaders seven innings or one seven and one nine?
[SPEAKER_00]: One seven and one nine.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mariella plays 50 games a year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: with the scandal of the Ohio Conference.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where I teach, we have quite a good baseball team.
[SPEAKER_00]: They hold the Division III World Series there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right now, it's going on right now.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we've won it a couple of times.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we go south and play about 18 six-inning games, or 15 games.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we play doubleheaders all the time from late March on.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they get in a lot of games.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it's quite a scandal, really.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what they do.
[SPEAKER_00]: The coaches won over 500 games or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who were some of those that made it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you remember any of the names of the Texas players?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we had two boys that were a year ahead of me.
[SPEAKER_01]: They did all the pitching until my senior year.
[SPEAKER_01]: A boy by the name of Norman Bryce signed with the Yankees before he got out of school.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we had another boy, Dick Metcalfe, that signed with the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then we had a boy by the name of Barkley that played with the Dodgers organization.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had several boys that played in the Texas league later.
[SPEAKER_01]: Luke Winburn and Lloyd Rigby.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rigby was a terrible major leaguer, but he was a star in the Texas league for years.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had a boy by the name of Morris Sands that played with Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mel Kravish that played with Boston Braves.
[SPEAKER_01]: Clyde McDowell, their second baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had a boy by the name of Jack Conway that played with Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jack Conway.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had...
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm talking about the
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't mean it's signed and just bought a cup of coffee in a minor league.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm talking about play public, not play ball, OK?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Branch had a very promising pitcher, but he never quite made it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a great year in Newark, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Branch and Metcalf could both throw as hard as anybody in college could throw.
[SPEAKER_01]: A good year at NERC, he had a pretty good year with the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_01]: He came up with a good screwball.
[SPEAKER_01]: He did not, somewhere, he lost his fastball when he hurt his arm or what.
[SPEAKER_01]: But after the war, he never did come back.
[SPEAKER_01]: Norm Brown.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nick Gibbs was a screwball if there ever was one.
[SPEAKER_01]: One of those million-dollar arms with 10-cent heads, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he went to Boston at the end of the season.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the screw was down.
[SPEAKER_01]: They took him to Boston, and then Albert Graham was another one from the open Texas down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Both signed with the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: Both went to Boston for a look.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they were going to send Mick Gibbs to Syracuse.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, naturally, he didn't want to go.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I'll come up here to fish.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't want to fish with the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: He never did make it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Neither did Albert Graham.
[SPEAKER_01]: But they played a little out, you know, the Red Sox farm games.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's an amazing record output for those years when college ball wasn't that emphasized.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Texas University, they had good coaching.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the reason they had good teams, everybody, every ball player, high school kid in Texas wanted to go to Texas to play ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't have a bunch of other baseball-minded schools that would recruit these kids.
[SPEAKER_00]: Another good college team, maybe a little earlier, was Alabama.
[SPEAKER_00]: They turned out a lot of great football players.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever play Alabama?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't play anybody but these Texas League teams that were training in this area.
[SPEAKER_01]: And early, they made it to squad games, and we played a few games with Texas League.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Babe Ruth, they still talk about her.
[SPEAKER_01]: Home run that Babe Ruth had from Clarksville.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, really?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was playing clear over the street, in front of the football stadium.
[SPEAKER_01]: over the right field.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, were you familiar with Park Field?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I've seen pictures of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is it on the site of the present field?
[SPEAKER_01]: I wanted to play baseball so bad that I was working when I was 17 years old for $0.25 an hour, stringing gravel to build a bridge across Blanco.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I had the opportunity to go to school in a Model A Ford.
[SPEAKER_01]: with some other boys.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's five of us.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it cost $6 a month.
[SPEAKER_01]: $30 a day, that's what they paid us for gas and oil.
[SPEAKER_01]: These two older boys, both fire-bated captains, both got the doctor's degree.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're Nash brothers.
[SPEAKER_01]: I rode back and forth three years for Kyle out here.
[SPEAKER_01]: My senior year, Frank Lane and I lived in the clubhouse at Clarkfield.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had showers and everything else.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had a little old radio in the bed.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we watched dishes at Ms. Patterson's boarding house for 40 people twice a day for a meal.
[SPEAKER_01]: She served boarding house style, where they just put the stuff on the tables, you know, and you pass it.
[SPEAKER_01]: We watched dishes for a meal and lived at Clarkfield my senior year.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's how I went to school during the Depression.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's how bad I want to play baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: You liked your studies, though, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: In studies, I started out fifth grade kid.
[SPEAKER_01]: P.E.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't like it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And my sophomore year, first semester,
[SPEAKER_01]: I took a physics course.
[SPEAKER_01]: They told me later, the dean called me in and told me that I couldn't get credit for this.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, because I hadn't registered for it properly or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I went back to the professor.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had to turn in a blue book.
[SPEAKER_01]: I made 87 on my final exam.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got my blue book, a note from the professor,
[SPEAKER_01]: But as far as he knew, I had attended class regularly.
[SPEAKER_01]: I made a B plus in the course, 87 on my final exam.
[SPEAKER_01]: I still didn't get paid for it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I asked Dean, I said, well, what am I here for?
[SPEAKER_01]: Am I here to learn the rules and regulations of decriminalization, or am I here to learn?
[SPEAKER_01]: You can't take away from me what I learned.
[SPEAKER_01]: After that, I dropped out of the PE deal.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I've been there long enough that I picked my professors
[SPEAKER_01]: And I took a lot of economics.
[SPEAKER_01]: I took logic, ethics, and a lot of psychology, and all that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I took courses.
[SPEAKER_01]: I knew that I didn't want to...
[SPEAKER_01]: The two-hour courses to go to the gym, teaching you how to play drop the handkerchief, and teaching kids at school, I knew I didn't want to teach.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't want to.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I took courses that I thought would help me live
[SPEAKER_01]: to help me make a living.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've always maintained that there's a big difference between a college graduate and an educated man.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's a big difference.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just because you finish college, you're not an educated man.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I took courses.
[SPEAKER_01]: I studied under one of the most brilliant men that I've ever known.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was Dr. Clancy A.
[SPEAKER_01]: economics professor.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I took every course that he had to offer, even postgraduate work.
[SPEAKER_01]: And all kinds of economics, agricultural economics, and several psychology courses, and magic, ethics, this type of thing, geography.
[SPEAKER_01]: I picked my professor and picked my course.
[SPEAKER_01]: I finished, I completed enough work, enough hours to get a degree.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I lost.
[SPEAKER_01]: the time that I had put in with each, that didn't count.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't have a degree outline.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, I went my four years, finished, played my baseball four years, signed with the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: You asked me about education.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's... No history?
[SPEAKER_01]: Sir?
[SPEAKER_00]: History?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what I teach.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, I had to ask for history.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that's history of the English.
[SPEAKER_01]: Those stuff are basic.
[SPEAKER_01]: You have to take those things.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I'm talking about my legacy.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's a great difference in professors.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was a Dr. Clark that taught English history.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought he was a real privileged man.
[SPEAKER_01]: You could go to his class and go to somebody else, and it's English, same field, different professor.
[SPEAKER_01]: You get a different perspective altogether.
[SPEAKER_01]: I took the class and I'm the Dr. Clark.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I thought, here's an opportunity.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's how I found my history.
[SPEAKER_01]: I completed enough work.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't even...
[SPEAKER_01]: Some of the... We had to buy our own books, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I took courses and classes and courses without even buying a textbook.
[SPEAKER_01]: I did a little research and made a collaborative with most of those professors.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you take notes, and you know what most of them want, it's what they've expounded here, and that's what they're going to ask you.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you remember that, you can go ahead and pass the course.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, among your colleagues, how many would you find a lot in common?
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, Facebook.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you find many players who had an interest such as you had?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Bobby Doerr and I were good friends.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bobby's been here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've just been here a year.
[SPEAKER_01]: I built a home up here on the hill when I bought this home on the day.
[SPEAKER_01]: My son lives up there now.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've got a basement in that home and a stairway going down into the basement.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've got the Red Sox, the Spaniards here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got the batting order, baseball bat.
[SPEAKER_01]: And down on the end is a brown bat, World Series bat, with all these boys' autographs on this bat.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the history of the Browns today.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Bobby Doar and I were good friends.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's come through here years ago when I lived in San Marcos up on the hill up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he liked the country and western music and lived outdoors.
[SPEAKER_01]: Our wives were.
[SPEAKER_01]: together a lot, and we lived together in the same building in Florida, Springtrain, lived near each other.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bobby and I, when we were on the road, Bob's wife was over at my house and my wife was over at her house, one of them, had a boy the same age as my oldest daughter, and I'd like basically been
[SPEAKER_01]: If I need something in Boston, I call Pesky to get me this or that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went up there one time and Pesky was going to meet me at the airport.
[SPEAKER_01]: Made reservations for me at the hotel.
[SPEAKER_01]: The day I got there, the Red Sox manager was fired that day.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Pesky was named manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was one of the top coaches.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was named manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: end of the season, the last five games I went up there to see.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went up there because Bobby Doyle was with the Toronto Bowl Club and I wanted to go up there, I wanted to visit with Bob, Johnny, and, oh, what's... Zimmer, Don Zimmer, was fired.
[SPEAKER_01]: In case you didn't know, he picked me up at the airport and had to get in because he was managing the Bowl Club at the end of the season.
[SPEAKER_01]: But this...
[SPEAKER_01]: Blue Ferris, we still get the Christmas cake, exchange Christmas cards, telephones, I run with them all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I saw some boys this last May when we were up there, a year ago, that I hadn't seen in a long time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Clem Driver and some of those boys.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe Dobson, I hadn't seen in a long time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was in St. Louis, they had the 25th anniversary
[SPEAKER_01]: of the 46th World Series team, and the St. Louis Cardinals played in the Dodgers.
[SPEAKER_01]: This was in 71, and all of the old Red Sox players were there, and the St. Louis football players were there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Several of our boys were already gone, passed away.
[SPEAKER_01]: St. Louis was nearly intact.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe Garagiola was a catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Red Shane Bass, all those boys, Stan Musial, and their ball club was nearly packed.
[SPEAKER_01]: By that time, I think the Higgins, Rudy York, several of our boys were there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I saw three or four of these boys that I hadn't even seen since 1946, last year, if I'm not mistaken.
[SPEAKER_01]: Leon Carberton,
[SPEAKER_01]: Some of those boys were there in 1947.
[SPEAKER_01]: I hadn't seen them till last year.
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't come to St. Louis until 1971.
[SPEAKER_00]: Have you got any pictures of yourself you could autograph for us?
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you what.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've lost some pictures, but I sent a whole box of pictures to Fred Graham in Dallas.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's the headband of the Hall of Fame fan.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I wanted them back because I'm 71 now, and all the pictures I've got, what I've got, I want to keep.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're making copies.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're going to mail them back to me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I haven't gotten them back.
[SPEAKER_00]: Could we leave our names and addresses with you so you can
[SPEAKER_00]: Absolutely.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd be happy.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd be great.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sure.
[SPEAKER_01]: Maybe name an address.
[SPEAKER_01]: What do you want?
[SPEAKER_01]: Just a card, a business card or something?
[SPEAKER_00]: What do you mean?
[SPEAKER_00]: PayPal?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, you can put yours on this.
[SPEAKER_02]: OK.
[SPEAKER_02]: Thank you.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd have to...
[SPEAKER_00]: cross out this one side because that's his, right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you put yours on the other side.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right, yours is on the back.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just right here, right there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then I'll know which is which.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, gentlemen, I've enjoyed this.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was great.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd like to say somebody that's truly interested and knowledgeable about the game.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I enjoy it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Nothing like it is at this time?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, I guess the older I get, the better I used to pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right.
[SPEAKER_01]: But there's some things here that I didn't know that this media guide, I get one of these every year, in this media guide,
[SPEAKER_01]: In here, it's got all the Red Sox scales here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've got the best earned run average of any Red Sox pitcher since 1920.
[SPEAKER_01]: 294.
[SPEAKER_00]: Very good.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I hold the record, all-time record, for one and nothing victory.
[SPEAKER_01]: was seven and over.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I've got the best won and lost percentage since Babe Ruth.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's two ahead of me, won and lost percentage.
[SPEAKER_01]: Smokey Joe Wood, Babe Ruth,
[SPEAKER_01]: Then I'm third, and one in last percentage.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cy Young is behind me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Grove, Kinder, Cornell, Tannehill, Westboro, Lewis Teon, Joe Dodson, Leonard, Mays, and Lee.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's in that order.
[SPEAKER_01]: And on our run there is Smokey Joe Wood, Cy Young,
[SPEAKER_01]: All those guys pitched more or less in the dead ball area before 1920.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I've got an earned run average of .294, which is the best since the dead ball area.
[SPEAKER_01]: The next one to me is Ellis Kinder with .328, the next earned run average.
[SPEAKER_00]: 1944 you had .226 ERA.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a great year, 18 and 5.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was the year that I was waiting to go into service.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was fortunate to have a high draft number to start with.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was not inducted early.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could have gotten a deferment.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was farming, ranching, agriculture, producing food and fiber for our country.
[SPEAKER_01]: I told them no.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm a primary, my occupation is a baseball player.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll go when I'm called, I'm not going to volunteer.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then early, in 1944, they quit taking free Pearl Harbor from us, over 25 years of age.
[SPEAKER_01]: I left here, I knew that I was going to be playing baseball somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I joined the Red Sox, Oakland, D.C.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched batting practice that day.
[SPEAKER_01]: Three days later in Boston, I pitched opening day in Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: I pitched nine innings and beat Philadelphia Athletics 2-1.
[SPEAKER_01]: And hadn't had one day in spring training, I hadn't pitched any batting practice to anybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: What I did, out on the farm out there,
[SPEAKER_01]: My little daughter's called, she's forty-four.
[SPEAKER_01]: I put her in front of the woods head.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got me a satin string or wagon sheet or what have you.
[SPEAKER_01]: I tied it up here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had about half a dozen baseballs.
[SPEAKER_01]: I marked off sixty feet here and I'm throwing.
[SPEAKER_01]: I marked off the strike zone and the red grill, that's what the strike zone is.
[SPEAKER_01]: Number one, two, three, four, five in the middle.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I would throw six balls, pick them up, run in.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was working, said, 12, 14 hours a day anyway.
[SPEAKER_01]: My legs were in shape.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's the only throwing that I did.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I was getting ready.
[SPEAKER_01]: I figured if I go in the service, I'm going to play.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went to Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: I won 18 and lost five.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was the leading pitcher in baseball at the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: This was in early August.
[SPEAKER_01]: That year, Harold Neuhauser won 29, and Virgil Trout won 27.
[SPEAKER_01]: I won my 18th before either one of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I left Boston on the ninth day of August.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I was 18, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But then the Battle of the Bulgers happened.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then my time came.
[SPEAKER_01]: They called for me, and I went.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a good hideout.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had the opportunity.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I was called, it was in the papers, a man came to me in Washington.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because I was a four-year university and this and that in baseball, he was going to get me a direct commission.
[SPEAKER_01]: I told him, no, I don't want that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, there's people in here that are more deserving than I am, that have been in there longer.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I won't accept it, even if you could get it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, besides that, I've got to come back here and face, be a baseball player.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't want them hollering at me about being a lieutenant sometimes.
[SPEAKER_01]: They did have this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Dickey got to be an officer in the Navy.
[SPEAKER_01]: He came back and don't think that the Volcker didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't associate with his fellow teammates.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was with the Army.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he heard from it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wasn't very smart, but I didn't want this.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't want the deferment, so I went.
[SPEAKER_01]: And fought World War II with a baseball bat.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was out here with Class A pass, living up on the College Hill.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was with the P.E.
[SPEAKER_01]: department.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had two classes a day.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had the nurse's class at ten o'clock in the morning for P.E.
[SPEAKER_01]: and I had the administrative officers at four in the afternoon.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's all I did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Orders came out of Washington to get these athletes out of the states, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there was three, there were about six of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: We went, 3rd of March we left here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Went to the South Pacific.
[SPEAKER_01]: And on to the South Pacific.
[SPEAKER_01]: They gave it, we had about 140 football players.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had tennis players, Don Burch and the, all on that ship going to the South Pacific.
[SPEAKER_01]: We ended up on Saipan.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's been about six months there.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't far from where they bombed Japan.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were just attached to the 13th Bomb Wing of the 23rd Corps.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were special service units.
[SPEAKER_01]: We played every day if we could.
[SPEAKER_01]: It didn't rain.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was three teams that provided us
[SPEAKER_01]: Two teams on 10-1 on Saturday on the airport.
[SPEAKER_01]: We went to Guam, we went to Iwo Jima, but in Iwo Jima they put us all back together in American and National League.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we played seven game series on Iwo Jima for the entertainment of the GIs.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's how I fought World War II with a baseball bat.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was the only pitcher over there that ever pitched a night in Boulder.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were just playing for less than one beer a day, you see, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we had, oh, Enos Slaughter and Howard Pollack and all, Joe Gordon, a whole bunch of them, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Max West, Walt Dudnick, and all the way up to Bertie Teddes was captain.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was the head of one of these teams, the old Detroit catcher, you remember him.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Billy Hitchcock.
[SPEAKER_01]: that managed Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_01]: Billy Hitchcock was the captain.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Buster Mills was a lieutenant.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the three officers that we had.
[SPEAKER_01]: The rest of us all in this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wherever some big star general could have the influence, that's where we'd go.
[SPEAKER_00]: OK, this is Art here, and I'm on the back.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can read all that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that would be great if you could
[SPEAKER_00]: Get some pictures for us and sign them and add to our collection.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let me get these pictures back from the Hall of Fame thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: I sent most of them up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've got some more pictures.
[SPEAKER_01]: I moved in here and moved.
[SPEAKER_01]: I built a new home out in Iraq, I did, four years ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: Moved from down here out there and then moved here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've got some pictures.
[SPEAKER_01]: that I want to keep my K-5.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're somewhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, this has been a great interview.
[SPEAKER_00]: Thank you so much.
[SPEAKER_01]: Talk about Lou Boudreau batting against him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boudreau is leading off.
[SPEAKER_01]: Matos
[SPEAKER_01]: he's going to be taken at first pitch, get a hit of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he took a hell of a cut and hit a home run off of it, beat the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: And later, in Boston, he was, he came up with a man on first and second, tying and winning runs on base for second.
[SPEAKER_01]: I remember this, when he outsmarted me, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was trying to get ahead of him and he was looking.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he hit the home run on the first pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, Woodrow, I know he's going to buck.
[SPEAKER_01]: The front's in order, he's got the front, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I threw the high fastball so he couldn't buck the ball on the ground.
[SPEAKER_01]: I pitched the ball up here.
[SPEAKER_01]: He took the damnedest cut you ever saw.
[SPEAKER_01]: That burned me up.
[SPEAKER_01]: I charged into the plate and I said, you Joe Colley's masterminded son of a bitch, bump that goddamn ball like you're supposed to.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went on back and he bumped it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw the man out at third.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know why, but he had the next man bumped, even with one out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Still man on first, second, hit him, but he got bunted over.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I knew what Boudreaux was doing, but he had hit this home run on me in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm trying to get a hit of him here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know he's going to be taking a strike, trying to get on there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's the one to run.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I laid one in here and he hit a home run.
[SPEAKER_01]: I told you that before.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I know what he was doing that day.
[SPEAKER_01]: When he did, he took this cut.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd taken one cheap shot at me against that short fence in Fenway.
[SPEAKER_01]: And if he doesn't hit it out, then he's going to bump.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a good bumper to have him back.
[SPEAKER_01]: If he doesn't, he's going to take a cheap free swing at me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know what he's thinking.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then he came back, and he did bump.
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw the man out of the third.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I know.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I told him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, bump the drum ball like it.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're back here in Austin at Ard's home and just had a return from this interview with Tex Hewson down in San Marcos.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought there's a little bit of time left in our tapes, we might just comment on some things we thought about or we noticed in connection with the interview.
[SPEAKER_00]: What were your thoughts about Cecil Texhewson?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he seemed like a very forthright gentleman who was an astute student of the game, no question about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He knew exactly what he wanted to do at all times, apparently.
[SPEAKER_02]: Didn't want to be interrupted too much when he was on the mound.
[SPEAKER_00]: When he was talking.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, right, right.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had to squeeze in.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was very willing to talk and picked up on anything we might suggest.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got progressively more cordial, I thought, as things progressed.
[SPEAKER_00]: The tape probably will have it, but several how many times he spoke, we enjoyed talking to such knowledgeable baseball people as we do.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then near the end... Well, aren't we?
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, let's face it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, there's no... Former president of Sabre?
[SPEAKER_00]: No question about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's nice to be reassured.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then near the end when he spoke about... How much he enjoyed it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've heard that from a number of people.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, many of them haven't been interviewed or like this job.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's experienced, you can tell that.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you can tell how he was paraphrasing it, not parroting sometimes that interview that John Kelso did, that clipping I gave you.
[SPEAKER_02]: Same words.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's got it down.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm sure he's...
[SPEAKER_00]: So we got a lot of things that were short in that interview.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought he was a little bit nervous.
[SPEAKER_02]: At the beginning?
[SPEAKER_00]: Throughout the interview, speaking of his physical condition, he seemed a little bit...
[SPEAKER_00]: Tentative?
[SPEAKER_00]: His hands seemed to shake.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was nervous.
[SPEAKER_02]: I noticed he kept working his fingers when he was talking.
[SPEAKER_00]: Although he spoke quite clearly and forthright.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know if he had some kind of an allergy or a little...
[SPEAKER_00]: No problem there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He looked awfully frail, I thought.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Really, I thought he would be more robust than he is.
[SPEAKER_00]: The encyclopedia said his plate weight was 195.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I'd say...
[SPEAKER_00]: He's still 6'3".
[SPEAKER_00]: 180, maybe.
[SPEAKER_02]: But that's all right for his heart's sake.
[SPEAKER_02]: But 71, that's...
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it's just on the edge, you know, of the 70s when the climate sets in.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're facing another soon.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, indeed.
[SPEAKER_00]: Won't be long.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we really enjoyed it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Art sat on the chair kind of catty-cornered from the couch in which
[SPEAKER_00]: that I sat on the other end of the couch with my mic in between us, and Arch Mike was on the table in front of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: There weren't any lulls, I don't think.
[SPEAKER_00]: He started right in.
[SPEAKER_00]: He almost started before I got my tape recorder going.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was all primed and ready to go, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was a lovely home.
[SPEAKER_00]: How do you describe their house?
[SPEAKER_00]: New house, ranch style, buffalo.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ma'am, you might be interested in this.
[SPEAKER_02]: When he left baseball in 1946, he went back to San Marcos and he bought 400 acres up on a hill for 38,000, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: over $38,000.
[SPEAKER_02]: Can you imagine what that property is worth today?
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a beautiful development.
[SPEAKER_02]: He developed it, by the way.
[SPEAKER_02]: When we came off Highway 12, we came up the Houston Drive.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about that?
[SPEAKER_02]: You're driving a Cadillac and you... No, it was a Lincoln, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, it was a Lincoln, not a Cadillac.
[SPEAKER_02]: You turn off on Houston Drive, your own street, and you come to a big
[SPEAKER_02]: beautiful ranch type house.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's quite impressive.
[SPEAKER_00]: He brought it back?
[SPEAKER_02]: In 1946, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He bought the house?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, this present house he just bought about a year ago.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he bought that whole land, that whole development there, 400 acres for I think it was $33,000, $38,000, something like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then when he came back, apparently he moved somewhere else.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came back and the lot that he occupies now in the same development that he bought, he paid $34,000 just for that one little lot.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he's a man of means, I guess you could say.
[SPEAKER_00]: Beautiful house.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's got a satellite dish out in the back where he brings in all the Boston Red Sox games, watches every Boston game.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't believe this loyally to his club.
[SPEAKER_00]: Isn't that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you see, I think it was fostered by his great admiration for Tom Yawkey, who was the owner of the Boston Red Sox when he came up.
[SPEAKER_02]: Mr. Yawkey was noted for being very kind and generous with his ballplayers, although, according to texts, Yawkey put the management in the hands of regular professional managers.
[SPEAKER_02]: But nevertheless, I'm sure Yawkey
[SPEAKER_02]: rewarded these players every now and then for good performance, I'm sure of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he played his whole career at Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: Goes back for reunions.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, and he goes to spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he goes out every spring.
[SPEAKER_00]: Went to Haven, Florida for spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he has a satellite dish and picks up all the games.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's amazing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've never run across that kind of loyalty to one's team in these old-timers I've talked with.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, many of them played many teams, so it's kind of... Yeah, that's true.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just had the one team.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it wasn't that long a career, actually.
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: His arm must have really gone bad there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Although he says he was on the way back.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, don't they all say that, then?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he won a few games there in 49.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was four and two.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was 533, but McCarthy didn't like him, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, wouldn't it be interesting if you could go back to McCarthy now and discuss that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Without tipping your hand, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know if I could.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd tell some wild stories about Joe McCarthy's drinking.
[SPEAKER_00]: Incredible.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't understand how a man could have been retained as a manager on two prestigious clubs with that kind of a record.
[SPEAKER_02]: When he managed he was good apparently, but when he was on a bender he was totally incapable.
[SPEAKER_02]: When he went on a bender he was away from the club, but when he was with the club he was a good manager apparently.
[SPEAKER_02]: He must have been doing something right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, he had, again, good material.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, he was fortunate there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Probably with the Cubs and Yankees and the rest of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: He won pennants with all of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where is his standing in the all-time win situation?
[SPEAKER_00]: He might have an encyclopedia there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, managers' ratings.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're just checking up an encyclopedia on,
[SPEAKER_00]: McCracken's managerial record is number one, 24 years, 641 winning percentage.
[SPEAKER_00]: 614 winning percentage.
[SPEAKER_00]: 614.
[SPEAKER_00]: And now it's tangled.
[SPEAKER_00]: You have too many losing years.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: That would be fair.
[SPEAKER_02]: That would be quite so.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know if Buster Mills was the manager.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ray James.
[SPEAKER_02]: He won the most World Series games, so 63.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh yeah, I didn't look up McCarthy.
[SPEAKER_02]: McCarthy was in ninth series and he won 43 in third place.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wait a minute.
[SPEAKER_00]: His World Series percentage?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, 0.698 first.
[SPEAKER_00]: OK. Well, he's a pretty good manager.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had 13 losses, which is number seven on the list.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had 30 wins, which was second.
[SPEAKER_02]: And games had 43, which was third.
[SPEAKER_02]: But the percentage of wins was the highest.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, remember when the Yankees were sweeping four straight, I mean, how else?
[SPEAKER_02]: They won four straight in 32, 38, 39, and then four in two in 36, four in one in 41, and four in one in 43.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, how else?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, so we've shown that McCarthy's a pretty good manager in spite of everything, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: But I would think that the management would have been pretty, you know, not sharp enough
[SPEAKER_00]: careful about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was as alcoholic as we would love to believe.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wasn't still on sleeping with that kid.
[SPEAKER_02]: There again, as I said, I think in the tape, when a guy's got statistics like that, especially in World Series, I mean, you take those chances.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mrs. Houston arrived late in the interview and
[SPEAKER_00]: after this refreshments, but we were getting ready to leave.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if we had taken them, I bet it would have dragged on another hour and a half, and we'd have eaten supper there, at least.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, about 3 o'clock, he announced that the Texas Longhorns were on them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was an old Longhorn.
[SPEAKER_00]: We got the idea.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wanted to wrap the interview up and watch the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we were already equipped, and I suggested, well, you don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's go on.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we went on another hour after that, and more.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he was in no hurry to end the thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I really haven't had too many experiences.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've had a few where they like to want to go on and feel a little disappointed when they do leave, but he was still wound up.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's been doing a lot of talking to, I'm sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a tiring experience for him.
[SPEAKER_00]: When he got out of there, he didn't have his air conditioner on either.
[SPEAKER_00]: He forgot about that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was so talkative.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a good athlete, pretty good hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where does he live?
[SPEAKER_01]: In Mississippi.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's been coaching at some college there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He stayed with the Red Sox for a while as a coach.
[SPEAKER_01]: Worked at Louisville.
[SPEAKER_01]: Southern Mississippi University.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a baseball coach and coordinator of some of this stuff.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's been there for years.
[SPEAKER_00]: In 47, I got your record here.
[SPEAKER_00]: It tapered down a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were you having problems that year?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_00]: You were beginning to, what happened?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that's another long story.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had, this started back in, well, when I was in the service, actually, or before that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a bad elbow.
[SPEAKER_01]: Finally, I pitched too long with it, I guess, and I had a bone swerve out of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And in 1947, the circulation went out completely.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was pitching against the Yankees in Fenway, and I never had anything hurt me as bad in my life.
[SPEAKER_01]: It felt like they had disarming advice.
[SPEAKER_01]: It felt like I had an iron ball on my ear.
[SPEAKER_01]: I bounced the ball up to the plate and walked off.
[SPEAKER_01]: And immediately they sent me to, within five minutes, this circulation came back.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was limited in this right arm.
[SPEAKER_01]: Came back.
[SPEAKER_01]: They sent me to neurosurgeon, Dr. John Hodgson.
[SPEAKER_01]: They thought I had a pinched nerve.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said that there was... examined, found out there was limited circulation.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, you don't need me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm an aerial surgeon.
[SPEAKER_01]: I made an appointment then with Dr. E.D.
[SPEAKER_01]: O'Neill, who was the foremost vascular surgeon.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'm sure that they had gotten reports from Dr. Thompson.
[SPEAKER_01]: O'Neill examined me the next day, walking down the street,
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't even take...
[SPEAKER_01]: I took my coat off.
[SPEAKER_01]: He asked me to hold my hands up.
[SPEAKER_01]: I held my hands up, brought them down.
[SPEAKER_01]: This one's still black, this one's red.
[SPEAKER_01]: His diagnosis was that the sympathetic nerve was in spasms.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had contracted and wasn't relaxed.
[SPEAKER_01]: The solution here is to cut this...
[SPEAKER_01]: the sympathetic nerve back there and relax it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went back to the ballpark, reported to Joe Cronin, told him what O'Neal had said.
[SPEAKER_01]: We needed to do this surgery.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Joe asked me, he said, when are you going to have it done?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, Joe, I'm not going to have it done now.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, why?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'm not satisfied with Dr. O'Neill's analysis of the situation.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, he's one of the world's best.
[SPEAKER_01]: They brought people royalty from England over here for Dr. O'Neill to do surgery on.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I want to go back and talk to the neurosurgeon, Dr. Hudson.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went back and I asked Dr. Hudson.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, if I have this type of surgery done,
[SPEAKER_01]: Will I be able to pitch again?
[SPEAKER_01]: Dr. Hodgson told me, he said, I've had people come to me that have had this type of surgery that couldn't play a piano or use a clap rack.
[SPEAKER_01]: They've come to me for corrective surgery.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I'm not telling you that a man of O'Neill's caliber did this surgery, but I'm just telling you what happened.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well, doctor, if I have this gun,
[SPEAKER_01]: You're going to do it.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a miracle.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not going back till later.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I sat around Boston for six, seven weeks.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had people, doctors, who'd read about this, that would take, have a day off, come to the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they came in to the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd sit around doing it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they discussed my case.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had me on a drug to stimulate circulation.
[SPEAKER_01]: They did everything, run tests.
[SPEAKER_01]: And one doctor, a young doctor, an American border surgery man, told me, he said, well, I can determine whether it's a sympathetic nerve infection.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, we'll go to the hospital.
[SPEAKER_01]: Made a formal regret at the hospital.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I can inject Novacaine into the ganglia of that nerve and deaden it, which will have the same effect as cutting.
[SPEAKER_01]: It will relax it.
[SPEAKER_01]: They put me face down on that table that's only on that side of the outside corner.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he's got to get with his big needle, file needle, he's got to get into it.
[SPEAKER_01]: right under the third thoracic vertebra to get into the ganglion of that nerve.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I could feel that thing go off.
[SPEAKER_01]: I squeezed the sawdust out of that table.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when he hit the bone here, well, he finally, anyway, he had a nurse here all the time, had her there checking him for him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nothing happened.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, well, maybe, maybe that we didn't get
[SPEAKER_01]: an efficient or effective block.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's come back the day after tomorrow and we'll do it all over again.
[SPEAKER_01]: We went back and did the same thing again.
[SPEAKER_01]: Got so much snow that came in my bloodstream that I felt like I was floating up drifting, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, I'm satisfied that we got an effective block.
[SPEAKER_01]: It is not the sympathetic nerve.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's the spasm.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, what I wondered, why didn't a man of O'Neill's caliber think of something like this, you know?
[SPEAKER_01]: Anyway, I came home.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was supposed to go to Dr. Albert Ochsner in New Orleans.
[SPEAKER_01]: On the way home, Dr. Albert Ochsner died, the foremost fascist man in the country.
[SPEAKER_01]: I made about 20 trips to San Antonio, back and forth.
[SPEAKER_01]: They finally diagnosed the trouble.
[SPEAKER_01]: They'd had the x-rays.
[SPEAKER_01]: They'd done everything they could all the time I was in Boston that lasted six weeks.
[SPEAKER_01]: Injected Novacaine into the spleen and side of his muscle up here and got a case of blood pressure.
[SPEAKER_01]: We went through all this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anyway, they cut a segment out of the muscle in my leg up here.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is in 1947.
[SPEAKER_01]: I get home Thanksgiving Day.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then I went to, back to Johns Hopkins where I was supposed to be.
[SPEAKER_01]: at the end of the season, but I didn't make it to the end, to have this elbow operated on.
[SPEAKER_01]: But that's George Bennett.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went there and had this elbow operated on in 1947, and I got home Christmas Eve in May.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Dr. Bennett would not operate on it for two reasons.
[SPEAKER_01]: The first thing, I don't need the operation if I'm not going to fix it in the end.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the main reason is, with the limited circulation, it wouldn't heal.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, not enough blood circulation.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wouldn't heal properly.
[SPEAKER_01]: But after I got the blood circulation restored to a degree, then I went back.
[SPEAKER_02]: So, how was it the next season then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I went back.
[SPEAKER_01]: They told me then, this was done late in December, that I wouldn't be able to fish 100% until June.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went back in 1948, and I had to throw.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was swell up.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was having trouble.
[SPEAKER_01]: May the 15th, cutting down time to the 25-foot limit, they optioned me to move.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were going out to make the Louisville.
[SPEAKER_01]: I told Joe Cronin, I said, McCarthy's managing the Red Sox at this time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cronin had moved up as president, mostly.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I told Joe, I said, I'm not going to Louisville.
[SPEAKER_01]: McCarthy had the total say as to who he kept and who the players or trades and what have you.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I told Joe, I said, I'll tell you what I'll do.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll go back to Austin.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll make my own arrangements with my staff tonight.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I live 30 miles from Austin.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then if I'm through, my family and wife and kids will be at home.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, if I could pitch at Louisville, I could pitch here.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I came back to Austin.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played, stayed in Austin from May the 15th through July.
[SPEAKER_01]: I finally pitched nine in the ballgame in Austin.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I called Joe Cronin and, around the office I was at, and Joe just asked me, he said, Tex, I want to ask you one question.
[SPEAKER_01]: Can you help this ball club?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, Joe, I can help your ball club if I'm used to it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, without even putting the phone down, he said, well, make your own arrangements, and we'll reimburse you when you get it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Come on back.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I got back, McCarthy didn't hardly recognize me at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: I pitched seven and one-third innings in about three or four different balls.
[SPEAKER_01]: I gave up one hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Dale Mitchell, Cleveland, got a base hit off of me between short and third on a ground ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: The only hit I gave up.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had me throwing every day in one game in particular.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was up in the first inning, didn't get the ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Again in the third, fifth.
[SPEAKER_01]: I told Larry Woodall, I said, Larry, I said, I can't be used like this.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could pitch five innings, six innings, or two innings.
[SPEAKER_01]: But this thing was sitting up swell up and getting fluid up.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I was trying to help.
[SPEAKER_01]: I told Larry, I said, I will not be able
[SPEAKER_01]: to do justice to myself or the ball club, either one.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, I warmed up four or five times today, I'll be in the bullpen again tomorrow.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've got to have some power in the play, regardless of whether I throw in the bullpen or the ball game or what.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wasn't joking, I just wanted to play.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I told Larry that, he told McCarthy, McCarthy
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well, him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, black him, he's not going to help us anyway.
[SPEAKER_00]: So in 49, did you stay with the clubhouse the rest of the season?
[SPEAKER_01]: I stayed through 48.
[SPEAKER_01]: 1949, McCarthy's still there.
[SPEAKER_01]: In 49, I was 100%.
[SPEAKER_01]: And down in Florida, I pitched good balls.
[SPEAKER_01]: Struck out some music, came over, shook hands with me later, said, glad to see you back.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, feeling good.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we opened this evening in Washington.
[SPEAKER_01]: Three days, I didn't pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're going back to Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jack Kramer's supposed to pitch against the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't have a short neck or something, and that fixed the ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, Ali Reynolds.
[SPEAKER_01]: He inbounded the fourth day of the season.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we get to the seventh inning.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a one-on-one ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ali Reynolds got a base hit just past Bobby Doerr's glove and drove in the run.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's Doerr from second arc.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was taken out for a hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had to pitch seven innings, give up two runs, six hits, struck out five.
[SPEAKER_01]: The next game I started was 33 days later in Chicago, and I hadn't started a game since.
[SPEAKER_01]: And at the end of the season, I told Joe Cronin, I said, Joe, if McCarthy comes back,
[SPEAKER_01]: Get rid of me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm going to quit.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not going to quit on you until I'm healthy.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the ultimate.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I said, I'm not going to buck my head against a stone wall either.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not coming back.
[SPEAKER_01]: If McCarthy comes back.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they sold me after McCarthy was rehired under certain conditions in October.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Red Sox sold me to the New York Jets.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the Johns Hoffman contract was the same money I was making.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I didn't report.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't want to go.
[SPEAKER_01]: Changing leagues, National League, living in New York.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I just retired.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't, I refused to report.
[SPEAKER_01]: They sent Jack Kramer instead of me over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I went on the voluntary retirement list.
[SPEAKER_01]: And June of 1950, McCarthy fired himself by getting drunk again on a vendor.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Red Sox had put it up to him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was an alcoholic.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know whether anybody knows that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But that's the reason he left the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_01]: When he came to Boston, he brought his own trainer that would carry his whiskey for him to the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I could tell you stories for an hour about Joe McCarthy.
[SPEAKER_01]: about his, about the problems that he had, that I had with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the day that McCarthy, they put it up to him, the rest of us, that if he got drunk on a three or four day deal, you know, then they put it up to him.
[SPEAKER_01]: But if he ever did that again, he fired himself.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was locked up by a cabinet, a make-up cabinet, a slaughter cabinet.
[SPEAKER_01]: The phone rang.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had to go outside to prove.
[SPEAKER_01]: And if Bobby Dorff and Boston want me back that same day, they'll probably let me.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I had already had to go on a voluntary retired list.
[SPEAKER_01]: That requires 60 days to get off of the retired list, voluntary retired list.
[SPEAKER_01]: Either I had to go on a voluntary retired list or get backlisted from baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went on the voluntary retirement.
[SPEAKER_01]: If I go back, it's June now.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then it takes me 60 days before I can get off the retirement.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then it's September.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I just said, hell with it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've already quit.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm retired.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know what I want to do.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm going to stay up here as long as I can.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'll stay here as long as I can.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know whether you want this McCarthy drinking deal on here.
[SPEAKER_00]: I interviewed McCarthy.
[SPEAKER_01]: You did?
[SPEAKER_00]: What?
[SPEAKER_00]: 1975, up in Tattawanda there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I didn't know much about the drinking.
[SPEAKER_00]: I did ask him one question about where he met his wife, and he didn't like that question.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just said probably in a bar or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I gathered he was familiar with some taverns.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I'll tell you what.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you some stories, then, if you've got time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, why not.
[SPEAKER_01]: When McCarthy was with the Yankees, you read stories about McCarthy wasn't going to be here.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hurt himself.
[SPEAKER_01]: He slipped in the bathtub and hurt himself.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you what I saw when he was with the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were playing the Yankees a doubleheader.
[SPEAKER_01]: McCarthy wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_01]: The second game had started.
[SPEAKER_01]: And out in left field out here, there's a big field here where the ground crew was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here comes McCoy in the uniform.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's bumping the wall kind of like this, coming down the left field.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, foul line's right next to the stand.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's come on in to the dugout.
[SPEAKER_01]: And later on, one or two of the Yankees said something about an old man riding a white horse, drank white horse guts.
[SPEAKER_01]: Later, in the season, in 1948 or 49, I mean, I was pitching the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_01]: McCarthy was on one of these vendors.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tom Dowd, the man you're seeing here, was our traveling secretary.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was an ex-alcoholic, converted.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was National Football League pitcher during the offseason.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Tom Dowd was McCarthy's custodian here.
[SPEAKER_01]: He stayed right with him all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: He might let him have a jacket or two, but it'd make him go eat.
[SPEAKER_01]: If McCarthy got on a bender, that was the main thing, he wouldn't eat.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he just wanted to drink.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he continued that for three days.
[SPEAKER_01]: So in St. Louis, and Tom Dowd and I left Joe McCarthy in the hotel room.
[SPEAKER_01]: We locked him in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's drunk.
[SPEAKER_00]: The manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: We get to the ballpark, I'm guessing, just before game time.
[SPEAKER_02]: So help me, people, this is the truth.
[SPEAKER_01]: Whenever McCarthy would get on one of these vendors, Joe Cronin, who was president of the ball club, would have to come out and take over the ball club.
[SPEAKER_01]: We left McCarthy in his hotel room.
[SPEAKER_01]: He calls the house detective.
[SPEAKER_01]: The house detective lets him out.
[SPEAKER_01]: He went by the bar and had a couple of double scotches.
[SPEAKER_01]: He comes to the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: And as I open the door, there's no tunnel things back there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm dressed, going to go take my warm-up.
[SPEAKER_01]: And here's McCarthy, standing here.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's got this fan, a man, and he's talking to them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I walked by and saw this.
[SPEAKER_01]: He thought it was Joe Cronin.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, Joe, please don't get on me.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I knew you when you was out in Frisco still sucking that high-tech.
[SPEAKER_01]: He thought it was Joe Cronin had come up to take over the ball pit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then, during the game, I guess, Crowley was the trainer for them guys.
[SPEAKER_01]: He moved up here with them.
[SPEAKER_01]: He carried his scotch from a coffee to have a drink during the ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: When he's on one of these things, the ball game period, he was sitting here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Vernon Stevens was in a slump.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was hitting bad.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he popped up with a basic load.
[SPEAKER_01]: And old Vernon was his good competitor, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Vernon was, he just batted himself on, McCarthy's sitting here, hitters my ass.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never saw such lousy pop-up hitters or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know whether you want this on here, but to tell you what,
[SPEAKER_01]: Vernon said to McCarthy, he said, go to hell, you drunk son of a bitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: Get off of my back.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what he told me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've seen McCarthy sit on the bench half inebriated.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bobby Doyle's playing second base.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's made 10 All-Star teams, one of the best second basemen to ever live, and look at Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: McCarthy never played Major League Ball at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: McCarthy's sitting here trying to tell him how to play the hitters.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he finally, McCarthy couldn't get Doar's attention.
[SPEAKER_01]: He gets a white towel and he gets up here, move over you dumb son of a bitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: So help me, that, I couldn't take it.
[SPEAKER_01]: That kind of stuff didn't go with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the way I got treated, Sam Meade was a good rookie out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: McCarthy had such complete control of that boat
[SPEAKER_01]: that you had to go into his office and get permission before he could order back the rope.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sam Neely had dropped the fly barrel in the sun, lost it in the sun in the Sunfield Lake, Mississippi.
[SPEAKER_01]: That caused a squall.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Sam went in, he didn't have but one bag left.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had to go in McCarthy's office.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he told McCarthy, well,
[SPEAKER_01]: permission to order half a dozen bats."
[SPEAKER_01]: McCarthy said, "'That's hell,' said, "'I thought you'd come in here to order a glove,' said, "'That damn ball you dropped the other day,' said, "'Henry would have stuck it in his ass pocket.'"
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's the kind of, you know, comparing us with the Yankee ball club.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, well, I couldn't take this.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't want to, I didn't have to.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the reason I quit when I was 33 years old.
[SPEAKER_01]: The last year I fell at 49, I was in two ballgames.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had good luck against the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, the Yankees and Buster Aiden McCarthy didn't like me, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: The first game I ever pitched in the Yankees stadium, I got beat.
[SPEAKER_01]: The next, the 41 and 42, I beat the ball club seven straight times.
[SPEAKER_01]: I held the record for beating the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's when they had the good ball club.
[SPEAKER_01]: Keller, Hendricks, DiMaggio, Hickey, Roth, Prosetti, you know, the whole works over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was fortunate.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd rather beat the Yankees once than St. Louis Browns for somebody else's pride.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I hadn't ever done anything for McCarthy.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think he resented it from the day I called Cronin and Cronin put me back on the ball club without ever consulting him.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's when I, from that day on, I was in the doghouse with McCarthy.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I'm just telling you some of the things that I witnessed.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the reason that I told Cronin, if he's coming back to manage this ball club, I will not be back.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'm not going to quit on you and Mr. Yawkey, but I'm going to quit.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I did.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the day McCarthy was fired, I could have gone back.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was invited back when Steve O'Neill took over the ball club.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he do this while with the Yankees?
[SPEAKER_01]: Some of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: He must have.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the reason they got rid of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't understand this.
[SPEAKER_00]: How can a guy keep a job like that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I know this, people.
[SPEAKER_01]: Today, that story would have been written.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know the story about McCarthy's drinking was written.
[SPEAKER_01]: They consulted with me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I helped the editors with it.
[SPEAKER_01]: The story was written by various, I'm sure it was two in New York.
[SPEAKER_01]: They knew the truth, but he was such a big man, big name, that they wouldn't bring him.
[SPEAKER_01]: They refused to bring him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now I'm telling you, I'm telling you people, so listen, I'm telling you the truth about this situation.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I don't care about Hurton McCarthy.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I don't care as long as I'm telling you the truth or who, I don't care if they have it for publication.
[SPEAKER_01]: I talked to a man who's right here.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's been three people here.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's a man from New York who worked for the New York Times.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's an author.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's not a sports writer.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's just like you people, good sports knowledge.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was here maybe a two hours.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was writing a book, not on what you see in the game, but the in-depth, the feeling, the inside.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's written a book.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's on a bestseller list.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's been with New York Times 25 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's going to send me a book.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he's writing a book on the players, the inside, the feelings, the emotions, what happens.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's been two or three people here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Especially, I've had interviews for the last couple of months.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've been honored enough that I'm going in to be inducted into Texas Sports Hall of Fame on June the 5th.
[SPEAKER_01]: Since that was released to the press nationwide, of course,
[SPEAKER_01]: Jack Corby and Y.A.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kittle and a bunch of them going in.
[SPEAKER_01]: Since that time, I've had a lot of people, a lot of calls, a lot of interviews.
[SPEAKER_02]: What will I deduct from these wages?
[SPEAKER_01]: The fifth of June.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's last week from yesterday.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the... Congratulations.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the state fire ground out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: But, I don't knock around people.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's got four or five reporters covering the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there's a man down there writing a book about the rivalry between the Red Sox and the Yankees, the history of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I wore out just to see these reporters talking to him down there in Winter Haven.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wonder if, uh,
[SPEAKER_00]: McCarthy got fired from the Cubs for the same reason.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know why he left.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know exactly why he left the Yankees, but I'm just assuming that that's why.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because he, I know this.
[SPEAKER_01]: There were several times when he was not with the Bulls that they made excuses for.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the Red Sox had to have known that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But they thought with Tom Dowd here, Tom could take care of him, you know, shake him up.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he did, to a degree.
[SPEAKER_01]: But every once in a while, he'd get on one of these.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wouldn't eat.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he'd get ill and cough, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: But everybody.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, as the other tape ran out, you were speaking about 49.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hope you don't use that same word.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean the language.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't care.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't want to, but you really have to use the language.
[SPEAKER_01]: to get my point across about McCarthy and his exact words that he spoke.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you were speaking about 49 when you pitched on the fourth day, and then not till 33 days later.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then you went into McCarthy's office.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, wait a minute.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got this wrong.
[SPEAKER_01]: This was in the end of 48, see, where I went back from Austin here, up there, in 48.
[SPEAKER_01]: I asked McCarthy, just as politely as I could do,
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, would you consider starting me a ballgame?
[SPEAKER_01]: I hadn't pitched nine in seven years, just released.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I would like to know for next year, or now, I would like to try to pitch nine in.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pick a spot for me or something, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he thought about it reasonably.
[SPEAKER_01]: He considered that.
[SPEAKER_01]: The next day it came back to me.
[SPEAKER_01]: McCarthy said,
[SPEAKER_01]: Now you're out.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I'm not.
[SPEAKER_01]: Are you out?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I'm sorry I'm taking all your time.
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: I talked to a sports writer from Dallas the day before yesterday.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've got the, he sent me the thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't even read it yet.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got it today in the mail.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: We talked 45 minutes on the telephone about this baseball ball thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wanted to know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I told him, I'm taking all your time.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I got as much time as you've got.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well, what about the cost?
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, them newspapers pay a mess.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, don't worry about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Are you ready?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I'm ready.
[SPEAKER_01]: McCarthy, very nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: He talked like he considered that.
[SPEAKER_01]: The next day, he came back to me.
[SPEAKER_01]: that McCarthy had said, who the hell does he think he is trying to tell me how to run my pitches?
[SPEAKER_01]: Now that's what I did.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's when I asked the coordinator, if he's coming back, I told him to get rid of him.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when he left, he fired himself.
[SPEAKER_01]: I knew that.
[SPEAKER_01]: They hired him back.
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't hire him right away.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was in October.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got the word that he'd been rehired, and the bowels were sold to the New York cops.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I think they rehired him under those conditions.
[SPEAKER_01]: If he ever did it again, he was fired.
[SPEAKER_01]: He fired himself, but he got bound to Jim, early Jim.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you get an illusion streak, it starts, you know, or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know what comes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, I suppose things had worked out right.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there have been no problems in McCarthy.
[SPEAKER_00]: How long do you think you might have gone on?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't have any idea.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you think you had a good outing, that one game?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I feel sorry for any young pitchers or anybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: You cannot pitch for 33 days.
[SPEAKER_01]: You elevate your mind here.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're thinking about, if I don't do good, I'm out of here.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is my last chance.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you're not thinking about the hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're not thinking about baseball and how to pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're concerned about what hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I don't like to see two or three of the Red Sox pitchers pitching now.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know whether you'd keep up with them.
[SPEAKER_01]: But pitchers like Jeff Sellers, an avid starter here, they start him every eight or nine or 10 days, start him three or four times.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is not right for young pitchers.
[SPEAKER_01]: They send him back to Louisville.
[SPEAKER_01]: the other day.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nobody can fix one of those things.
[SPEAKER_01]: For your job is on the line if you don't do it.
[SPEAKER_01]: If I were a manager of a bar club, and you bring somebody out of the pool, for example, somebody gets failed at the start of the year, you bring one of your aides to start it, you bring him up, you go start it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I would like to see him start him at least three times, tell him your job is not on the line today, you've got to get three or four more chances, guarantee him that, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then he'd feel better, and I think he'd be in pitch better.
[SPEAKER_01]: But not knowing when he's going to be, unless somebody gets hurt or double-edged, and they have to come in on those conditions.
[SPEAKER_02]: What's so bad about spring training and when the rookies are coming in and have such a brief time to show their stuff?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, when I was optioned out in 1940, 1941, I was with the boat club I hadn't pitched in to speak of in 1941.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we were in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe Cronin called me and said, Tex, I'm sorry, but we're sending you to Louisville.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, Joe, I think you're making a mistake.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I meant it.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't popping off, wasn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, Joe, I can pitch as good as anybody you've got on this ball pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: Grove was about through pitching every Sunday.
[SPEAKER_01]: The other pitchers, I know with my own heart and mind,
[SPEAKER_01]: that I can pitch as good as he can.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, well, go on to Louisville and prove it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went down to Louisville, won seven straight ballgames in Louisville, made the All-Star.
[SPEAKER_01]: 15th of May, 1st of July, I was recalled to Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they sent two of the pitchers that I told him about, that I could pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: They sent two of them to Louisville when I went up.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I had that much confidence I wasn't
[SPEAKER_01]: popping off or anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: I knew in my own heart I couldn't throw as good as it did.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, I'd like to pick up on something you said earlier.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were always close to the plate.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: Always.
[SPEAKER_02]: A guy like Culler, you never knew where it was going.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Didn't a hitter, when he went up against you, have sort of an edge?
[SPEAKER_02]: Because he knew you were going to be close to the plate all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'd get wood on it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: Whereas with Culler, my God, you're
[SPEAKER_02]: bailing out for your life half the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, those are the kind of pitchers that you're talking about that have a good day and can pitch you no hits.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never even came close to pitching no hits.
[SPEAKER_01]: I pitched a couple of two hits.
[SPEAKER_01]: And a three-hitter, I think I pitched a three-hitter against Feller in that one-to-nothing game.
[SPEAKER_01]: And a three-hitter in the one-to-nothing game will be Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: for the Saints to play off.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, to make the league championship in 46.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I would give up an average of nine hits a ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: On an average.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, if I pitched 275 innings, I would allow 260 base hits.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or roughly.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wasn't way there.
[SPEAKER_01]: But my base on ball was so limited.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I got
[SPEAKER_01]: I had some long balls, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I didn't walk three men ahead of that home run, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, a home run was one run instead of two or three or four.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, that's one thing that, as I see it now, as I get older, I wasn't real smart or I would have made more pitches bad eventually.
[SPEAKER_01]: But by the same token, you can see these pictures today that are nebulous.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it's three and two on everybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: I sit with Hank Sore in Boston about 1981.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was the old pro football player, umpire to my colleague for years.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he and I sit together in Boston up in the press box over there, one whole ballgame.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was talking about these hitters that
[SPEAKER_01]: The pitchers, that are nibblers, start out with ball two on the hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, they need to challenge that hitter more, get something on the ball, get it over.
[SPEAKER_01]: You cannot pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could never pitch if I'm behind on the hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Three and one, stuff like that, where you've got to come in there with two.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think one of the worst nibblers I ever saw was Ralph Perry.
[SPEAKER_02]: Remember him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yankees?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, with the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't remember that about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a couple good years.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I've had a lot of long balls hit off of him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was the longest?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I guess the hardest hit ball that I can remember.
[SPEAKER_01]: was hit in this fourth game of the World Series in Boston by Enos Slaughter.
[SPEAKER_01]: He really creamed one, hit one.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hit one in the, or not in, the bullpens are here, the glitches here, he hit one in, way up in the glitches there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, a real nine down.
[SPEAKER_00]: After a,
[SPEAKER_00]: The batter does nail one on you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Next time up, do you try to move him back a little bit?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I never did too much of that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw it one man my last time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw it one man.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I released the ball, I didn't give a damn.
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's two ways to do it.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can throw to brush a man back, or you can throw to hit him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw this pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: By the time it left my hand, I was sorry to how it looked after.
[SPEAKER_01]: It went behind him, and it hit his grandstand.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a boy by the name of Thurman Tucker, a left-hand hitting outfielder for Jimmy Dykes.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I threw at Tucker, when I downed him, Jimmy Dykes cussed me forever.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's so many in the world for throwing at this guy with the dark, heavy glasses.
[SPEAKER_01]: I told him, I said, I told you to read my business, the little history behind it.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're playing in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Tucker was the kind of hitter that carried his betting average on his sleeve, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was base hit crazy.
[SPEAKER_01]: And later in the ball game, score tied and man on second, he out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tucker's catching me flat footed.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd already had three hits.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he bunnied, caught me flat-footed, beat it out, that's four.
[SPEAKER_01]: And if I had been a manager, I would have fined him the maximum.
[SPEAKER_01]: For bunnying in that situation, you can't drive in the time right with a bump, with two out.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I resented that to the day.
[SPEAKER_01]: When he came to Boston later, I told my catcher, I said,
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm going to change up, change this thing on Tucker.
[SPEAKER_01]: I told you about going to freeze the slider on the right-handed and left-handed.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're going to reverse that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I threw the slider in on Tucker.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hits the prop fly just over the first baseman's head.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's right in the center of the line here with backspin on it.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's hit number five.
[SPEAKER_01]: The next time he came up, I said, here, hit this one.
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw him kind of one on defense pitches.
[SPEAKER_01]: He beat it against home plate and it bounced 50 feet in the air.
[SPEAKER_01]: By the time I caught it, he was already across first base.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's six hits in a row.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, that's enough.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't tell anybody or say anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: I lowered the boom.
[SPEAKER_01]: But everybody in the ballpark and everybody knew because I did have good control.
[SPEAKER_01]: They knew it was on first base.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the reason I didn't like to throw it at anybody
[SPEAKER_01]: When I was in Kenton, the Yankees had a catcher by the name of White that was always probably given the knockdown sign against our ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_01]: The knockdown is usually the fist, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And some of us knew what he was doing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ordering the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I managed to get past that as you told me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Told the pitcher ahead of me, there's so-and-so there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I want you to knock him down.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's White.
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't do it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they told me the same thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Loosen him up.
[SPEAKER_01]: I did not throw at him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't throw at him just hurt him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw him high inside.
[SPEAKER_01]: He backs away like this.
[SPEAKER_01]: The ball hits his hand against the back of his back and broke three bones.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't play for six weeks after that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I didn't like that idea.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't mean to damage his career, hurt him in any way.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I didn't ever like for anybody, if I'm going to throw him out or loosen him up to a degree, I don't want nobody to know it was me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then I'll tell you another story.
[SPEAKER_01]: Vernon Stevens was St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_01]: Before the war, Vernon Stevens hit a home run off me in the 8th inning, tied the ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: In the 10th inning or 11th inning, he hit another home run off me in the 3rd inning, beat me in the ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: In the 46th, we was playing the Browns.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was pitching this day.
[SPEAKER_01]: Vernon Stevens came over to our clubhouse and he's petting me and feeling my arms and said,
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, how's your arm?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'm all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, well good.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, you're pitching today.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I'm kind of in a slump.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I'm glad you're pitching today.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I told him, my friend, I said, you're my friend, you're my buddy.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I'm telling you, just like a friend, you keep popping off like that, and I'm going to lower you just like flat as a dry cow chip on the Texas prairie if you keep popping off.
[SPEAKER_01]: So later in the season, I don't know, I got the second base, got a double, and that's enough to take a picture out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Changing pictures, I'm at second.
[SPEAKER_01]: Burns played short.
[SPEAKER_01]: I called him over.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I've been promising you something for a long time.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he had just doubled off the screen in right center field.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'm going to tell you something.
[SPEAKER_01]: The next time you come to the bus, I'm telling you like a friend.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, you're going down.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I've been promising to you.
[SPEAKER_01]: And if I don't do it, you're going to think I'm a coward.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, you just be ready.
[SPEAKER_01]: It'll be on the first kick.
[SPEAKER_01]: Vern gets up and cuts his big stents way down.
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw it at him right here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't throw it behind him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw it right here.
[SPEAKER_01]: He did a back flip, got up pretty fast, turned around and didn't say a word.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I told him, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did Tucker react the time you threw behind him?
[SPEAKER_01]: He tried to front fall and make me feel it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was going to run up and back like a wonder curtain.
[SPEAKER_01]: Fell on the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's one way they retaliate.
[SPEAKER_01]: They can, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was going to drag bump me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Make me cover the face.
[SPEAKER_02]: Run over me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bump into me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Crack that off.
[SPEAKER_01]: What a way.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, what's the next section?
[SPEAKER_00]: Spitballs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Emery balls.
[SPEAKER_00]: Grease balls.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I can tell you stories about that if you've got time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: By the way, the Texas Longhorns are playing Arkansas in the College World Series starting right now.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I play the Texas Longhorns.
[SPEAKER_01]: Roger Clements and all those boys, Texas Longhorns.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can pick it up later and read the papers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mike Raver was an old catcher, relief pitcher, and I started throwing spitballs at him once in a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mike told me, he said, you've got the best spitter of anybody I've ever seen.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we had two pitchers on our football team, Dick Newsome in the early 40s and Charlie Wagner.
[SPEAKER_01]: Charlie Wagner.
[SPEAKER_01]: They both told me that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I told that nurse of mine, I said, you old North Carolina hillbilly, I said, you're not coming back, you prude.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'll give you a thousand dollars to tell me how you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He denied it to his mother or anybody, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I knew.
[SPEAKER_01]: But, anyway.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that old Bobo?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no, not Bobo.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is Heber.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bobo was pictured for St. Louis in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was, but one day I threw a stick, once a day probably.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never threw it unless I had two stacks, or I never threw it unless I was in a big jam.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there was no use of throwing it because 90% of the time the batter is going to miss it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I would just with these two fingers, I learned to work with it and let the ball go just like Scott throws the court ball now.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, I'd split the finger with this.
[SPEAKER_01]: One day in St. Louis, George McQuinn, the first baseman,
[SPEAKER_01]: men on base, I stuck him out with a stick.
[SPEAKER_01]: A few days later, we were on the outpost, and I walked into the hotel.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe I'm warming up too much.
[SPEAKER_01]: I stuck George McCrim, rushed across the lobby,
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, Ted, you're cheating, son of a bitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, what's the matter with you, George?
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, you know you struck me out the other day.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I got halfway back to the bench.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I jumped that high.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I thought about that dirty son of a bitch doing that to me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, George, you know that didn't happen.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know I wouldn't do anything like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But there was one day with Fannie Yankees in Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: I heard a couple of men on, two men out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe DiMaggio up front, two strikes.
[SPEAKER_00]: I struck him out with a spitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe just swung right through.
[SPEAKER_01]: Side's retired.
[SPEAKER_01]: His head's caved up a bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know he said something to the third base coach about it later, to watch it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Later in the ball game, Tommy Hennig was a cop.
[SPEAKER_01]: Johnny Peacock, he knew when I had one loaded.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you'd watch him, you could tell nearly when I had one loaded.
[SPEAKER_01]: Peacock would get the cops in time to catch it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, the ball hit Peacock here on the end of the glove and rolled off across the red dirt here.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Art Fletcher, coach at the College of Film and Art, take a look at that ball, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: except to look at it a little.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right before the spot was on the ball, a red play picked it up, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And after the game, Bill Summert for some time, old Sea Pig he was called in short there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sea Pig?
[SPEAKER_01]: Sea Pig was his nickname, Summert.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he came to me after the ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, Tex, god damn it, I want you to quit throwing that thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, you got good stuff, you don't need it, and I'm going to retire in a year or two.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then after I retire, you can throw it all you want to, but don't embarrass me anymore.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he teach you how to do it?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just asked him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, you're not going to be back in a year or two.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'll give you $5 to tell me how you do it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here she is.
[SPEAKER_02]: We're still here about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: This is our wife, Gladys.
[SPEAKER_02]: How do you do?
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm Art Gilbert.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is Austin, Marietta, Ohio.
[SPEAKER_02]: This man lives in Austin now.
[SPEAKER_01]: They've lived in Austin several years.
[SPEAKER_01]: They used to be schoolmates back in the old days back in Ohio.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was fixing to demonstrate how I used to throw my splitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just turned that on, honey.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's getting warm in here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just turned it off.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I'm fishing, when I'm following through, right there, I've got it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cross-bore, swept.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I'm following through, out here, the balls are wet, everybody's looking here, I've got it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Whenever I've got it, that sun will pick up and catch it.
[SPEAKER_01]: If my glove was turned up here, you know, he'd give us that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd look, my glove's here, I got it, I walked through it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He knows it was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just this little, I just turned the tip of my glove up right there so nobody knows.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I loaded it while everybody looked in here, right off the field.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I don't know how the hell
[SPEAKER_02]: Some of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Gaylord Perry.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know yet.
[SPEAKER_01]: They searched him.
[SPEAKER_01]: They've done everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know if I did.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's always going through the motions.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Yankee manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had a special camera on him, Gaylord Perry.
[SPEAKER_01]: All the controversial Yankee managers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Billy Martin.
[SPEAKER_01]: They tried to catch him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tried everything they could.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's been more than one I've been through.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tommy Bridges over at Detroit later.
[SPEAKER_01]: Little Tommy had a good curveball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you what, one day in Boston, Tommy Bridges threw Ted a spitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: He swung it over the pit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ted asked the catcher right quick.
[SPEAKER_01]: Said, what the hell was that?
[SPEAKER_01]: And the catcher wouldn't say anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ted said, call for it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell him to throw it again.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, tell him to throw it again.
[SPEAKER_01]: Call for it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the catcher said something about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here it is.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Ted hit 210.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just let him drive the other side.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know if maybe it's oxygen or what.
[SPEAKER_02]: I heard a good line the other day.
[SPEAKER_02]: They asked Gaylord Perry why he didn't develop a knuckler.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he said, well, it's hard to throw a knuckler when you've got three centers for fingers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Obviously.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was a lot of them throwing it.
[SPEAKER_01]: This relief pitcher where the ball got away from Mickey Owen.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was a spitball one.
[SPEAKER_01]: It got away from Owen.
[SPEAKER_01]: The runner scored, you know, the Yankees tied the game.
[SPEAKER_01]: The spitball is mine.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can throw it just the same as my fastball and just let it go.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a claim to fame, but if you release it... What does it do?
[SPEAKER_01]: It just drops, is that it?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ball breaks down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do the fielders know you're throwing it?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just to catch it, that's all.
[SPEAKER_00]: What does it stir to you?
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw a spitter, a spitter a few times.
[SPEAKER_01]: A lot of ball games I never even threw.
[SPEAKER_01]: If I got a big lead or something, didn't need to.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had the spear hit one time, a boy, a big catcher, by the name of Kerman, a white shot, hit a home run off of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hit a spear for a home run.
[SPEAKER_01]: But that was after Jimmy Bloodworth, Detroit, I got hit on the stun and broke the stun.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was out for several weeks.
[SPEAKER_00]: You batting or pitching?
[SPEAKER_01]: I was pitching and the ball hit back in.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I just boom, boom, back in.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I didn't get the right pressure on this thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: The spitter didn't work.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tucker hit it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not Tucker, but Turner hit it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Big right-handed hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hit a home run in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the only hit that I remember giving up on that day.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't throw two bass the whole time I was here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Only in the spot where it was meant to go.
[SPEAKER_01]: And only with two strikes.
[SPEAKER_01]: No point in throwing the spitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: It counts one and one.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he misses it, he's still hitting.
[SPEAKER_01]: And no point in advertising it and getting everybody on you about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it's a good thing for pitchers to have this because the hitters, it's something else for them to worry about.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I used to agitate over Luke Sewell, the manager of the St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_01]: I would pretend to do it and show it.
[SPEAKER_01]: trying to, you know, and then he was a psychologist, and the hitters were psychologists, and I wasn't even about to throw one.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what Perry did a lot of times.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wasn't a little psychologist on the other, but it's not... Coffee, soft drink?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I'll tell you what,
[SPEAKER_01]: As you can see, I love baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I like to talk with people that know baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: People around here that don't know baseball and ask stupid questions.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like, where did you play when you weren't pitching?
[SPEAKER_01]: Or, I've seen some of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: People around here played a little semi-pro ball party 30 years ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: They know more about the game than I do.
[SPEAKER_01]: There were people here last year after the World Series.
[SPEAKER_01]: Several people asked me, when it was over, where did you go to cry?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, hell, I didn't go cry.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't go anywhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just turned the damn thing off and went to bed.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, I know what can happen.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a sports writer out in San Antonio call me, and he asked me,
[SPEAKER_01]: We talked for 30 minutes last year during the series.
[SPEAKER_01]: He asked me, he said, how did the players feel about the so-called jinx that the Red Sox can't win a play?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, the players don't think anything about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: They don't even believe in it.
[SPEAKER_01]: The players know what can happen.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, you people, you're having four trials.
[SPEAKER_01]: This one that started this, this is for some conversation piece.
[SPEAKER_01]: It makes a good story.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're the ones carrying it on.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I know what could happen.
[SPEAKER_01]: The game could have, any, the Red Sox were in four series since 65, 46.
[SPEAKER_01]: 46 could have gone either way.
[SPEAKER_01]: Slaughter story we talked about.
[SPEAKER_01]: And 75, anything could have happened.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, I mean, 67, it went seven games.
[SPEAKER_01]: 75, it went seven games.
[SPEAKER_01]: 86, it went seven games.
[SPEAKER_01]: The game could have gone either way in a series.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, when I'm pitching, I learn to accept defeat.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never learn to like it, but I learn to accept it.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's no other choice.
[SPEAKER_01]: All I did was try to remember why and how and try to correct it, try to be better the next time.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I never learned to like it, I learned to accept it.
[SPEAKER_01]: big feet on the play field.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did you like Joe Cronin as a manager?
[SPEAKER_01]: Real good, fine man.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought Joe Cronin was a good man.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was he still playing when you first joined the club?
[SPEAKER_01]: When I joined the ball club, he was the shortstop, playing shortstop.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then in 41, then Pesky came along, took over shortstop.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some of them blamed Cronin for
[SPEAKER_01]: letting Haley Reese get away.
[SPEAKER_01]: He belonged to the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was in love.
[SPEAKER_01]: And some of the sportswriters, being the story of Joe Cronin, didn't want to keep him.
[SPEAKER_01]: They sold him to the Dodgers because Joe didn't want to lose his job at shortstop.
[SPEAKER_01]: Propaganda or whatever.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think there's any truth to it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Pesky took over.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cronin was at shortstop, playing manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he did play some level.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he pinch-hit
[SPEAKER_01]: on numerous occasions.
[SPEAKER_01]: One of the best pinch-hitting exhibitions I've ever seen was by Joe Cronin.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're playing Philadelphia, four-game series.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe pinch-hit in four games.
[SPEAKER_01]: The first game, he pinch-hit, he had a three-run home.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's on Friday.
[SPEAKER_01]: He pinched it, hit a three-run home run.
[SPEAKER_01]: The first game of the doubleheader on Sunday, he popped up to the first base, pinch hit it.
[SPEAKER_01]: The second game, he pinched it with Matt on, and he hit a home run.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hit three home runs and four at-bats, drove in nine runs, and won or tied two of the three ballgames.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was him.
[SPEAKER_01]: 42, 43, he would still hit the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was his technique as a manager?
[SPEAKER_00]: How did he handle players?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was he pretty tough or easygoing?
[SPEAKER_00]: Or did he vary his approach with different types of personalities?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I thought that Joe was very even-tempered and easy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just like I said, he
[SPEAKER_01]: knew that you couldn't win them all.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the only time that I ever saw Joe get tough was when he had to, when he was forced to.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wasn't a tough man.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't cuss and raise hell all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I thought he was a good man.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was, for me, a good man.
[SPEAKER_01]: If he would have been with the Red Sox, if he had been the manager in 1948, I would have never been sent back.
[SPEAKER_01]: I would have been put on the reserve list, injured reserve list.
[SPEAKER_01]: But McCarthy had total control.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had never done anything for him.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he had the support, even down to ordered bites.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had that authority on both of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: that only when he was forced to did they see him again.
[SPEAKER_01]: And only on very rare occasions did he have a tantrum and close the clubhouse and eat the players out.
[SPEAKER_01]: It never happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: He always seemed to be easygoing from just what you can see in the papers and so on.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you wonder how he really is within the clubhouse and so on.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe was pretty diplomatic.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had pretty good psychology and all.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought Joe was a good manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't think McCarthy was a good manager, especially after I knew him with the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe McCarthy was the kind of manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jimmy Dykes, I think, described McCarthy better than anybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jimmy Dykes managed the White Sox for so long.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought Jimmy Dykes played good ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought he was one of the better managers when I played against him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He used to hit and run well.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had good personnel.
[SPEAKER_01]: Luke Apley and those people.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd steal the base at the right time.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he described McCarthy as a push-button manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: He could push a button and get a home run, or push a button and get, you know, a lot of offense there.
[SPEAKER_01]: When my daughter was five years old, she could have won with the Yankees, with the material they had, and the coaches they had.
[SPEAKER_01]: And all McCarthy had to do was write the line up and tape it up to the mailbox, and maybe change pictures or something like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: But they had tough coaches.